# Jagan Mohan Bishoyi

(+91) 890-8348-100 | jaganmohanbishoyi@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Portfolio | Nationality: Indian Address: Bangalore, Karnataka, 560066

# **Profile Summary**

I am a Development Lead by profession having expertise in front-end development. I have designed and developed web-based and mobile front-ends with modern, highly interactive UIs using JavaScript along with Angular and Ionic. I'm an enthusiastic collaborator, and a fast learner with creative problem-solving skills, good coding, and excellent communication skills.

## **Work Experience**

# People10 Technosoft Pvt. Ltd., Bangalore

# Development lead (April 2022 - Present)

Working in the development team to create reusable components for other developers and building packages to handle cross-cutting concerns and empowering developers to focus on business logic. More focused on developing the NPM library to be used across projects.

## Associate development lead (April 2021 - March 2022)

Implemented JWT to make the application more secure. Launched a Peer learning program in the team. Presented a talk on Test Driven Development (TDD) at the company Tech Talk. I have taken multiple front-end interviews for the company. Mentoring juniors and team members in technical areas including but not limited to best coding practices.

## Senior Software Engineer (March 2020 - April 2021)

Developed an Angular 9 from scratch. Migrated angular.js project to Angular 9. Responsible for the development of WordPress events and blogs for the client. Given Angular 9 training to team members.

### Sulopa Technology Pvt. Ltd., Bangalore

### Software Engineer (April 2018 - March 2020)

I started my career as a front-end web developer. Within these fascinating 2 years, I got the opportunity to work in a variety of technologies.

- Developed more than 40 fully responsive mobile-friendly cross-browser compatible static websites using HTML5, CSS3, proficiency in Javascript, JQuery, and Bootstrap, and more than 15 websites using WordPress.
- Developed 2 fully responsive web applications using Angular.
- Developed a hybrid mobile application using the lonic 4 framework, and published in Google play store and Apple app store.
- Was managing 50-plus websites in various hosting environments.

## **Projects**

## **OLAS: Jobs for K-12 Education System**

Generally, this application is about providing employment solutions to Districts/Schools. The school will create jobs and a candidate can apply for a job. They can search by zip code for the availability of jobs nearby. And this application has different portals and the super admin can impersonate another user to the application. I am responsible for:

- Create and maintain user-friendly web pages and optimize web applications for maximum speed
- Mentor junior front-end engineers to make the team more effective and take interviews
- As part of the team, ensure members adhere to our code quality and testing standards. And participate in code reviews.
- Collaborate with back-end developers and web designers to improve the usability

- Actively participate in the scrum meetings and the development activities (coding, documentation, deployment)
- Review business requirements and perform technical analysis of requirements and participate in the estimation process
- Maintain strong coding, compliance, and security standards by following coding best practices
- Participating in the design and implementation of new features
- Build reusable code and libraries for future use
- Building Micro-Frontend component-based architecture for standardized UI elements

Tech Stack: Angular 9, Server-side rendering (SSR), .Net, IIS

# Menuadda (Restaurant Management System)

It is a Visual Menu for everyone, One stop solution for all restaurants. An end-to-end restaurant management system that helps you manage and Increase the revenue for sure. We designed the admin dashboard using angular 7 and the consumer application using Ionic 4. I am responsible for:

- Converting prototypes to highly interactive UI
- Writing modular/reusable code
- Integrating UI with backend using REST APIs, JWT, OAuth, Webhooks
- Collaborate with back-end developers and web designers to improve the usability
- Mentoring / coaching Junior Engineers.

Tech Stack: Angular 7, Ionic 4, Node Js, Serverless, Elastic search, Cloudinary image processing, etc.

# Periplus (Travel Management System)

Generally, this application is about building itinerary and cost calculation, transport booking, hotel booking, and travel agent booking. I am responsible for:

- Converting Wireframes to highly interactive UI and writing modular/reusable code
- Collaborate with back-end developers and web designers to improve the usability and Integrate UI with the backend using REST APIs

Tech Stack: Angular 5, Node Js, Cloudinary image processing, etc.

#### Skills

- Time Management, Problem-solving, Creativity, Positivity, Adaptability, Active Listening, Flexibility, Organization
- HTML5, CSS3, Sass, SCSS, Javascript, Typescript, Bootstrap, Angular 2+, Ionic, REST API, Es6, webpack, Redux
- Unit Testing ( Karma, Jasmine, Jest )
- Git, Github, Bitbucket, WordPress, SonarQube, Web Hosting, JIRA, Trello, NPM
- Browser caching and storage using indexedDB, localStorage
- PWAs and server-side rendering
- Knowledge of NgRx
- Agile scrum development process
- Software development lifecycle (SLDC) and SOLID principles

# **Community Contribution**

NPM package: ng-password-validator | Links: NPM | Demo | Github

Google chrome extension: Password Generator | Links: Chrome Web Store | Web Application | GitHub

### Education

## Gandhi Institute of Industrial Technology, Berhampur

Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech.), Computer Science and Engineering (2013 - 2017)